Overconfidence. Counterintuitively, it's sometimes overconfidence that gets in a
person's way. You're used to the positive rewards of doing things quickly and
independently, an algebraic equation, a sales report with a high closing rate, a
dissertation. Because you're good at what you do, you can skip over certain details.
However, if you try to rush through speaking English, you'll end up skipping
crucial details. Furthermore, if you only rely on your own judgment about your
accent, particularly if it's spelling-based, short of the mark. What to do
about it? Start from scratch and make a conscious effort to get rid of your
preconceptions. Put yourself in the position of knowing nothing about
pronunciation, intonation, voice quality, word connections, etc. Then lay the
foundation with basic sounds and rhythms. Rebuild a new strong structure using the
grammar and vocab you've worked so hard to acquire.